袭击泰瑞之后没多久 玛莎就被酒吧禁止进入了
Martha was barred for an incident shortly after the attack on Teri.
找到你了
There you are!
脚踏两条船的懦夫 渣男
You cowardly, two-timing fuck.
你那晚很有种啊 竟敢堂而皇之地把那贱人带到我面前
The nerve you showed me the other night, rubbing that skank in my face.
好了 够了 玛莎
All right, that's enough, Martha.
你现在是我的敌人了 驯鹿宝贝
You've made an enemy of me, reindeer.
- 别以为我会放过你 - 玛莎
- Make no mistake about it. Martha!
- 希望你清楚自己干的好事... - 够了
- I hope you know what you've done... Enough!
- ...居然这样伤害我 - 玛莎
- ...in wounding me like this. Martha!
你那张轻浮的嘴 迟早会给你惹麻烦 小子
Your mouth's gonna get you in trouble, boy.
有那么一瞬间 我以为整件事会到此结束
For a moment, I thought that might be the end of it,
但她却开始 在我生活中的所有其他场合出没
but she just multiplied across all other areas of my life.
嘿 你们真该瞧瞧他女朋友长什么样 十足的丑八怪
Hey, you should see the woman he's dating. Pig ugly.
他自轻自贱 在臭水沟里找女人
If he stooped any lower, he'd be a hunchback.
好的 女士们先生们 你们好...
Yes! Uh, hello, ladies and gentlemen, s--
他是个驼背佬 卡西莫多
He's a hunchback! Quasimodo!
佝偻着背在臭水沟里找女人
Head in a gutter of skanks!
好啊 他来了 脚踏两条船的放浪先生
Yeah, there he is, Mr. Two-timing Slut.
千万别相信他
Don't trust him, guys.
他会许诺跟你上床 然后溜之大吉
He'll promise you sex, then sprint the other way.
这一切的一切 都让我不堪其扰
It was killing me, all of it.
不过 由于演出被玛莎破坏 我得以自动晋级决赛
A free pass to the comedy final on account of Martha ruining the gig
也算在一团乱麻的当下 给了我一丝慰藉
offered little comfort in the face of everything.
我考虑过辞掉酒吧的工作 搬家
I thought about quitting the bar or moving house
或者暂停发展喜剧事业
or pausing the comedy for a while,
但我不想再让她得逞
but I didn't wanna give her the satisfaction
让她对我予取予求了
of taking any more than she had.
所以我只好静观其变
So all that was left to do was lie and wait,
揣测她还有可能做出什么事来
questioning what else she might be capable of.
别以为我会善霸甘休 驯鹿宝贝 从我iPhone发送
《驯鹿宝贝》
妈妈 刚才有人朝我脸上泼东西
Mum! Someone just threw something in my face.
- 没事的 冲干净就好 - 天哪
You'll be all right. Just wash it out.
怎么了?
What's going on?
- 刚才有人攻击我 - 什么?
- Someone just attacked me! - What?
我还以为是强酸 还以为我要瞎了呢
I thought it was acid. I thought I was gonna go blind.
天哪 结果是什么?
Jesus. I mean, what was it?
我不知道 感觉是汽水 好像是可乐
I don't know. It was, like, a fizzy drink. It was Coke, I think.
可乐? 会不会是
Coke? As in, like... As in, like... like
健怡可乐?
Diet Coke?
我没工夫关注它的含糖量 唐尼
I wasn't paying attention to the sugar content, Donny.
- 天哪  - 是啊 不 当然
- Jesus Christ! - Yeah, no, of course.
是来过我们烹饪小组的那女人
It was that woman from the cooking group.
我走到窗边时 看见她沿着街道跑远了
I saw her running down the street when I came to the window.
是嘛 不 我好像对她有印象 对
Oh yeah. No, I... I... I think I remember her. Yeah.
她在泼我的脸之前说了 "去死吧 唐尼"
She said, "That's for fucking Donny," before she threw it in my face.
这究竟是怎么一回事?
What is going on here?
那个女人
She's this woman.
她这段时间
She's been
一直在跟踪我
stalking me.
她一直在跟踪你?
She's been stalking you?
慢着 她就是在脸书上骚扰我的 那个玛莎吗?
Wait, is this that Martha woman who's been harassing me on Facebook?
天啊
Oh my God.
她来过我家
She's been in my home.
你他妈的真是个白痴 知道吗?
You are a fucking idiot. You know that?
- 她跟踪你多久了? - 我不知道 六个月吧
- How long's this been going on for? - I don't know. Like, six months.
- 六个月? - 你报警了吗?
- Six months?! - Have you been to the police?
报过了 但警察没当回事
Yeah, I have, but they, you know, wouldn't take it seriously.
加上刚才发生的事 他们也许就会当回事了
They might if you tell them what just happened to me.
什么事? 有人朝你脸上泼可乐?
What, that someone threw a Coke in your face?
真不敢相信你会说出这种话
You know what? I can't believe you.
不 我不是那个意思 我的意思是...
No, that wasn't what I meant. I just meant...
天啊 我只是想说
Oh my God, I'm just saying, like,
这女人一天给我发好几百封邮件 他们都没当回事
if they don't take this woman sending me hundreds of emails a day seriously,
泼汽水这种事就更不会了
they're not gonna give much of a shit about a soft drink, are they?
那样的话...
Well, in that case...
虽然很过意不去 但是唐尼
I really hate to do this to you, Donny.
我觉得你最好还是搬出去吧
I think you'd better move out.
我搬到了基尔伯恩 跟在表演学院认识的两个人同住
I moved to Kilburn with two guys from my drama-school days.
房东是他们其中一个的父亲 所以我能勉强承担租金
One of their dads owned the flat, so it was just about affordable for me.
原以为住宿条件会很糟糕
I expected the absolute worst,
但当门打开 看见新住处的那一刻
but as the door opened onto my new place,
我对眼下处境的忧虑和沮丧 便统统烟消云散了
all my dread and frustration at the whole situation just vanished.
这里堪称完美 是一个全新的开端
It was perfect. A fresh start.
我又能把自己隐藏起来了
Anonymity again.
天哪 这地方太棒了
Holy shit, this place is nuts.
是啊 是难得一遇的好房
Yeah, it's such a find, honestly.
天啊 瞧那阳台
Jesus Christ. The balcony!
是啊 俯视为生活奔波的芸芸众生 总是感觉特别好
Yeah. Always nice to look down on people as they go about their lives.
我以为你在私立学校已经看得够多了
Thought you'd have done enough of that at private school.
两年没见 你都开始拿社会阶层开涮了
Haven't seen you for two years, already with the class digs. Good.
喜剧事业进展如何了?
How's the comedy going?
还不错 最近晋级了一个 喜剧新人比赛的决赛
Yeah, not bad. Got to the final of a new-act competition recently.
新人?
New act?
你混那行都五年了吧
You've been doing this for five years now.
照这个速度下去 估计到领养老金时都还没混出头呢
At this rate, I'll still be doing them when I'm picking up my pension.
你呢? 最近在忙什么?
How about you? What are you up to?
- 我正休学一年 - 在伦敦?
- I'm taking a gap year. In London?
是在工作吗? 想存点钱?
Are you working? Saving up or something?
没有 我目前靠存款过日子
Nah, I'm, uh, living off my savings.
还在寻找方向 享受自由
Finding my way. Enjoying my freedom.
我们的无线网是蹭楼下咖啡馆的网速超快 还能省网费
We steal Wi-Fi from the café downstairs. It's fast as fuck, so we save there too.
天哪 这地方也好得太不真实了吧
Fucking hell, this is insane.
背后有什么猫腻吗?
What's the catch?
好久没在你住的街区看见你 胆小鬼 朵起来了?
没种象个男人一样 跟我把话说清楚吗?
从我的iPhone发送
烦人的是 如我所料 弗兰西斯果然有所隐瞒
I found it tediously predictable that Francis had failed to mention
他和毕玖休学是为了实现他们...
that him and Bijou had taken time off to fulfil their...
探索文化和精神活性的使命
Cultural, psychoactive destiny, man.
就是嗑迷幻药 兄弟
Psychedelics, bro.
它会给你带来 前所未有的洞察力和清晰的思维
They give you an insight, a clarity, like nothing you've seen before.
我想也是
My thoughts exactly.
对于休学一年 大部分人会想到搭飞机旅行
A gap year, people think that means getting on planes and shit,
但其实在自家客厅 也能享受完整的往返旅程 兄弟
but you can do an entire round trip inside your living room these days, brother.
听起来真令人神往
This all sounds very riveting,
但不介意的话 我现在想拉屎
but if it's okay, I'd quite like to take a shit now.
这就是我现在的生活
So this was my life.
躲在卧室里 热气穿过地板蒸腾而上
Hiding away in my bedroom while the heat rose through the floor
墙壁被人类有史以来 最烂的音乐震得嗡嗡响
and the walls pounded with the shittest fucking music known to man,
而压垮我最后一丝神经的
feeling utterly overcome
是对玛莎那排山倒海般的恨意
with how much I hated Martha.
你跑哪去了?
iPhone发送
有人吗?
Hello?
我有个女儿 现在两个月大
I've got a daughter. Two month-old. Two-month-old, right?
我给她取名阿道夫 开玩笑的啦
So I called her Adolf. I'm joking! I'm joking!
你们在干什么?
What's going on?
她已经满三个月了
She's three months old.
真他妈见鬼
Oh, for fuck's sake.
快把那破玩意关掉
Look, just fucking get that off.
关了也没用 我们都看过好几遍了
No point. We've watched 'em all several times.
问这个或许有点失礼 但你的笑话为什么那么无趣?
This is gonna sound like a crass question, but why isn't it funny?
问诺里奇去 是诺里奇那地方的人无趣
Ask Norwich. It's Norwich that's not funny.
说真的 我们只笑了两秒钟 然后就一直坐在那儿为你感到郁闷
We laughed at it for two seconds, then sat around depressed as fuck for you.
就好比如果有人死了 谁都知道不能拿那种事开玩笑
It's like when someone dies, and you know you can't joke about it.
我都不敢再嗑迷幻药了
It makes me not wanna do acid again
生怕醒来发现自己 成了你笑话里的一个段子
in case I wake up inside your comedy routine.
抱歉 这是谁?
Sorry, who's this?
- 他是狄格西 新来的 - 你还挺自来熟的 是吧?
- That's Digsy. He's new. - Make yourself at home, why don't you?
别拿狄格西撒气 视频的事是玛莎告诉我们的
Whoa, don't take it out on Digsy. It was Martha that told us.
我差点立马解除了对她的禁制
I almost unbarred her there and then.
你没那个权力 肥仔
You don't have the authority to do that, you fat prick.
说句公道话 观众的反应过于冷淡了 其实有些地方还挺好笑的
To be fair, it's a lot funnier than the audience are giving you credit for.
- 确实 - 对 非常有趣
- That's true. - Yeah, marginally so.
不用可怜我 那是我第一次演出 我现在进步多了
Don't pity me. That was my first gig. I'm a lot better now.
我们拭目以待呢
Well, we look forward to seeing it.
是啊 在那之前 我想把那视频投影到墙上
Yeah, and until then, I'm thinking let's project that on the wall.
- 让整个酒吧的人都乐一乐 - 对
- Beam this cunt round the entire pub. - Right.
好吧?
Yeah?
我开始越来越长时间地在泰瑞家停留
I started spending more and more time around Teri's place.
本以为玛莎的那次袭击 会让她对我避而远之
I thought the incident with Martha would be the end of us,
但没想到 我们反而比以前更亲近了
but instead it bound us tighter than ever before,
泰瑞的经历使得她能更好地理解我
Teri's experience allowing her to better understand mine.
天哪 那群人真是混蛋
Jesus, those guys are such assholes.
你有告诉他们 你进入了一个喜剧比赛的决赛吗?
Did you tell them you have a big, fancy comedy final coming up?
没有 哪怕我真当上了 笑鸭年度最佳新人
No, I don't think the prospect of becoming the Laughing Duck New Act of the Year
他们也不会对我嘴软的
would have done me favors in a conversation like that.
等你把冠军奖杯抱回家的时候
They'll be laughing on the other side of their face
他们就笑不出来了
when you take home the crown.
我喜欢这态度
I like that attitude.
- 对了 别太习惯现在这样的好日子 - 不会的
- Don't get used to this, by the way. I won't.
- 太辣了吗? - 太辣?
- Too much chili? Too much?
天哪 泰瑞 这简直是地狱级的辣椒酷刑
Christ, Teri, they're gonna feed me this in hell!
天啊
Oh my God!
给 喝你的奶吧 小弱鸡
Here, drink your milk, pussy!
我感觉仿佛能看见来世了
I feel like I can see into the next life.
在泰瑞舒适的公寓里
And within the comfort of Teri's flat,
她感觉够安心 我觉得够私密
with all the safety she needed and all the privacy I did,
我们很快发展成了甜蜜的小情侣 其实早该如此的
we flourished into the couple we should have always been.
在某种奇怪的意义上 虽然得到了想要的一切
And in a strange sense, I'd gotten everything I'd ever wanted,
一段隐秘的恋情
a closed-door relationship,
但我内心却难以抑制地 对玛莎抱有某种扭曲的感恩心理
as I tried very hard not to feel grateful towards Martha in some fucked-up way.
你是何时发现自己 愿意和跨性别女性约会的?
When did you first figure out you were open to dating trans women?
大概是我问上帝 能否让我的生活更复杂一点的那天吧
I think I asked God one day if he could make my life more complicated.
你的性取向是什么? 如果被人拿枪指着头问的话
How do you identify sexually? If there was a gun to your head.
拜托 快扣扳机吧
Oh, please, pull the trigger.
闭嘴 混蛋
Shut up, asshole.
我可不会喜欢你的葬礼 还有那些悼词
I don't fancy that funeral. All the speeches.
"唐尼是个特别搞笑的好小伙儿"
"Donny was a top lad with great banter."
是只会有我奶奶去致悼词吗?
Will my gran be the only one that's speaking?
回答我 笨蛋
Answer, idiot!
我不知道 也许是双性恋吧
I don't know. Like, bi, maybe.
为什么会是双性恋?
And what makes you bi?
因为无论跟谁上床 我都感觉自己是个骗子
Because I feel like a fraud no matter who I sleep with.
那要怎样才能给你信心?
What's it gonna take to give you some confidence, huh?
说真的 认真想想
Seriously, think about it.
不知道你想过这个问题没有
I'm not sure you ever have.
我也不知道 那句话是怎么说的来着?
I don't know. What's that phrase?
就是关于...跳舞和自信的那句
You know, the one about... dancing and watching.
自信就是旁若无人地起舞?
Confidence is dancing like no one's watching you?
对
Yeah.
我不知道
I don't know.
就感觉说得挺好的
Just seems quite nice.
那很简单啊
Well, that's easy.
看吧? 小菜一碟
See? Piece of cake.
是啊 而且看起来还很蠢呢
Yeah, and you look like a total knob too.
我可是学了十年芭蕾舞 和两年踢踏爵士舞呢
Ten years of ballet, two in tap and jazz.
我妈想要的绝对是个女孩
My mom definitely wanted a girl.
来吧 我教你
Come. I'll show you.
不要
No way.
- 别害羞呀 - 不行 绝对不要
- Don't be shy. - No, not a chance in hell.
- 试试看嘛 - 不要
- Just try. No, no.
- 我会像个木头一样 - 少无聊了
- I'll sandbag you. - Oh, don't be such a bore.
好吧 我变成木头了
Fine. I'm sandbagging.
不 我现在是木头 不要
No. I'm sandbagging. No.
你要真想这么扯皮 我可以跟你耗一整晚
I'll try all evening, if that's what it takes.
不 过来
No. No. Come here. Come here.
怎么样?
So?
跟我在一起时 会觉得自己是骗子吗?
Do you feel like a fraud with me?
不知道
I dunno.
我们还没试验过呢
We haven't put it to the test yet.
见鬼 我在发抖
Oh fuck, I'm shaking.
没关系 我可以接受 过来
That's okay. I can work with that. Come here.
怎么了?
What's going on?
不 没事 我只是发现很难...
No, no. I'm... I'm fine. I'm just finding it hard to...
摆脱内心的偏见?
Shake off your prejudice?
拜托 别在前戏时说教
Please. No lectures during foreplay.
少来 别跟我说你不会觉得 我讲课的样子很性感
Oh, come on. Don't act like you wouldn't find me hot as a lecturer.
穿着权力套装 戴着女秘书风格的黑框眼镜
- Mm. - Power suit. Secretary glasses.
握着用来鞭挞你的教鞭
One of those pointer things to hit you with.
抱歉 不 我还没准备好
Oh, I'm sorry. No. No. I'm... I'm not ready.
对不起 我的身体就是没反应
I'm sorry. My... my body, it's... it's just not letting me.
别担心 没关系
Hey, don't worry. It's fine.
这是常有的事
Happens all the time.
- 是吗? - 是啊
- Does it? - Yeah.
- 我早有耳闻了 - 闭嘴
- So I've heard. - Shut up!
- 你想喝杯茶吗? - 好啊 当然
- Would you like a tea or something? - Yeah, sure.
好的
Okay.
真是奇怪
It was strange.
我的身体经历了那么多可怕的事情
After all the awful things that had been done to my body,
面对真正亲密的人却无法再勃起
I just couldn't lose myself in intimacy anymore.
似乎牵扯到感情 一切都令我不堪重负
Now there were feelings involved, it all just felt too much.
那些抚摸 爱意 和一再的确认
The touch, the love, the confirmation.
你元本是打算 同时睡我们两个吗?
从我的iPhone发送
抱歉 还是不行
Sorry, it's just not happening.
接下来的两周里 在多次尝试失败之后
Over the next fortnight, after repeated failed attempts,
我开始注意到泰瑞的一个变化
I started noticing a change in Teri.
几乎一整天都在床上度过
Days spent predominantly in bed,
穿着前一天的衣服 在家里神出鬼没地游荡
skulking around the house in yesterday's clothes,
模糊了白天和黑夜的界限 再没了往日的神采
blurring the line between night and day without her usual spark.
上午11点52分
你还好吗?
Is everything okay?
嗯 还好
Yeah, I'm fine.
然后我在夜里醒来 发现她仿佛缩进了自己的壳里
Then I would wake in the night to find her shrinking inside of herself,
如同折翼的天使
her wings clipped.
你还好吗?
Is everything okay?
天哪 别再问了
My God, stop asking that.
你有什么心事可以跟我说 我也许能帮上忙
Well, maybe if you explain, I might be able to help.
看看我的头发 唐尼 瞧它现在成什么样儿了
Look at my hair, Donny. Look at the state of it.
- 又打结成一团一团的怪样子了 - 我觉得很好看呀
- It's growing back in weird clumps. - I think it looks great.
难看死了 你心里有数
It looks horrible, and you know it.
我看起来好像阴间大法师
I look like fucking Beetlejuice.
好极了 你还笑得挺开心
Great. Now you're laughing.
怎么了嘛? 真的很好笑
What? That was funny.
听着 泰瑞 如果你不开心 是因为我们做爱时的尴尬局面...
Look, Teri, if this is anything to do with all this awkward sex stuff...
不 是你在做爱时给我的感觉
No, it's the way you make me feel during the sex stuff.
好像你身体的反应在证实
Like your body's manifesting
她那晚对我说的所有过分的话
all the awful things she said to me that night.
不是的 泰瑞 这跟那个完全没关系
No, no, Teri, it's got nothing to do with that.
是玛莎的事影响了我 才害我表现失常的
It's just the whole Martha situation. That's what's getting to me here.
我只是压力太大了
I just feel so fucking stressed.
但你有在想办法 解决这个问题吗 唐尼?
But what are you even doing to fix the situation, Donny?
鬼知道我们已经在家里窝了多久
We've been stuck inside for God knows how long now,
等着你想通了
waiting for you to figure it out.
我试过去报警了 但他们帮不上忙
Well, I've been to the police, but they were useless.
你有提过我被袭击的事吗?
Did you mention what happened to me?
当然了
Of course I did.
那怎么警察没来找我问话?
Then why haven't they been round?
因为你根本就没提
It's because you didn't say shit!
不是的
That's not true.
她袭击我那晚你就不让我报警
You stopped me calling them the night she attacked me.
还阻止其他人报警
You stopped everyone calling.
你恨不得让我 立马从酒吧消失 越快越好
You couldn't have whisked me out of that pub any faster.
- 我是想把你带到安全的地方 - 是啊 当然是了
- I was trying to get you to safety. - Yeah. Sure you were.
你自以为是的安全
The safety inside your own fucking head.
她说我看起来像个男人 唐尼
She said I look like a man, Donny.
你知道我听了是什么感受吗?
Do you know what that's like for me?
我不知道
No, I don't.
但无论如何 你看起来一点也不像男人
But for what it's worth, you don't look like a man at all.
这话从一直把我当男人看待的人 嘴里说出来 可真有说服力
Pretty rich coming from someone who's always treated me like one.
我当时真该站起来就走
I should have gone then.
我真该握住泰瑞的手
I should have grabbed Teri's hand
牵着她一起去警局
and brought her to the police station with me.
但最终还是羞耻感占了上风
But still my shame won out.
我不得不另寻他法
I just had to find a different way.
我把话说青楚... 你永远别想得到我 一刻也别想
我宁愿自尉十次 也不让你干我
从我的iPhone发送
我们不能指控某人自慰
We can't charge someone for masturbating.
不是自慰的问题 你看这邮件
It's not about the masturbating. Read the email.
发这种骚扰邮件应该是违法的吧
You shouldn't be allowed to send that.
就算有什么 她也在邮件里暗示不会靠近你了
If anything, her email implies that she's gonna stay away.
我觉得你没抓住重点
I think you're missing the point here.
我是在告诉你 对于你的指控 她会如何反驳
I'm giving you the arguments she'll come back with.
要以电子邮件为依据逮捕某人
To arrest someone on the basis of an email,
我们需要看到切实可信的威胁 或者具有攻击性的性骚扰
we need a credible threat or something sexually aggressive.
如果我是个年轻女人 而一个40岁的男人
If I was a young woman and a 40-year-old man
不停给我发邮件说手淫的事 这算切实可信的威胁吗?
kept emailing stuff about wanking, would that be a credible threat?
如果是女性被男性跟踪 我们会担心女方受到人身伤害
With male-to-female gender stalking, the threat of a man is physical.
男性通常更具有危险性
He carries more weight.
没有人比刀子更具有危险性了吧?
Nobody carries weight against a fucking knife, do they?
但凡我能看到任何证据 显示会发生暴力...
Again, if I could see any evidence that would suggest violence--
我的天哪 她正在毁掉我的生活
Oh, Jesus fucking Christ, she's ruining my life here.
在系统里搜索她的名字 玛莎·史考特
Type her name into the system. Martha Scott.
会有发现的 我告诉你
There'll be something there. I'm telling you.
好吧
Right.
是的 我好像搜到她了
Yeah. I... I believe I've found her.
这样吧...
Just... Tell you what...
要不我把你的...
why... why don't... why don't I get you your, um...
要不这么着吧 你到里屋来好吗?
Actually, why don't you just come through to the back?
我觉得最好还是让我的上司来看一下
'Cause I'd better get my... my supervisor just to look through this.
- 不好意思 我们在等人吗? - 对
- Sorry, is there someone coming? Yeah. Uh...
她来了
Oh, just... just now, in fact.
谢谢
Thank you.
下午好 我是乔安·卡尔瓦警探
Good afternoon. I'm Detective Joanne Culver.
所以 玛莎·史考特
So, Martha Scott.
对
Yeah.
我不能说太多
I can't say too much here,
但你只需要知道 她是一个非常执着女人
but all you need to know is she is a very serious woman.
执着到甚至曾经跟踪过一名警察
So serious that she once stalked a policeman.
好吧
Right.
我的同事告诉我 她不知道你的电话号码
My colleague tells me she's not in possession of your phone number.
对吗?
Is that correct?
是的 没错
Yeah, that's... that's correct.
很好 务必确保不要让她知道 好吗?
Good. Let's make sure we keep it that way, shall we?
好
Yeah. Yeah.
理想情况下 我们会希望你画出一个时间线
Now, ideally, you would draw up a timeline for us.
列出目前为止发生的一切 好让我们大致估计一下严重程度
Everything that's happened thus far, to give us a sense of the scale of it.
可以 那与此同时呢?
That's fine. And in the meantime?
我们会找她谈谈
We will talk to her,
警告她以后不要有过分举动
warn her regarding any future conduct.
太好了
Great.
然后呢?
Then what?
你会发现有了警方的介入 情况会大为改观的 邓恩先生
The presence of the police can change things, Mr. Dunn.
我明白 但你刚刚才说了
Mm, I get that, but you literally just said
她是一个很执着的女人 甚至跟踪过警察
she's a serious woman who even stalks policemen.
我们会尽力而为
We'll do what we can.
警察对玛莎登门拜访后 她忽然安静了下来
The police's presence at Martha's door brought with it a sudden silence.
诡异 可怕的寂静
Strange, eerie silence.
从我遇见她的那一刻起 她每天都会持续不断地联系我
Not a single day from the moment I met her did she not contact me.
如今却沉寂了下来
Now silence.
诡异 可怕的寂静
Strange, eerie silence.
几周过去了 我开始恐慌
Weeks went by, and I started to panic.
透过那些邮件 我能看到她所有不同的情绪
The emails allowed me to tune into every facet of her emotion.
知道她什么时候伤心了 什么时候想我了
I knew when she was sad, when she missed me,
什么时候生病 喝醉 或是生气了
when she was ill or drunk or angry.
现在只有一片空白
Now nothing.
我发现自己开始夜不成寐
I found myself awake at night,
事实上 我既担心又害怕
worried, terrified, in fact,
怕哪天一早起床 会发现她已经自寻短见
that I was gonna get up one morning to find she'd killed herself,
而我的收件箱里躺着一封邮件 说她是因我而死
an email in my inbox expressing that I was the reason why.
事件时间表 8月21日-玛莎来到酒吧
我在想念她吗?
Did I miss her?
我在内心深处对她念念不舍吗?
Was there some part of me that missed her?
怀念她的胡闹和关注
Missed the drama, missed the attention,
以及她会让我暂时忘却那个男人 泰瑞 我自己 还有发生的一切
missed the distraction from him and Teri and myself and what happened.
我在想念她吗?
Did I miss her?
而整件事里最奇怪的就是
And the strangest part about all of this,
我开始对着玛莎的照片手淫了
I started to masturbate over Martha.
做出这种会让我濒临破碎的生活
There was something so awful yet thrilling
愈加万劫不复的事情 是如此糟糕 却又无比刺激
about doing something that would devastate my life even further.
每次我都能很快高潮 继而在事后留下相同的疑问
I would come quickly every time and be left with the same confusion
那简直成了我高潮后的标志性困惑
that had become my post-orgasm trademark.
"我在搞什么鬼? 事情怎么会变成这样?"
"What the fuck was that? Where did that come from?"
她对我毫无吸引力
I wasn't even attracted to her,
但跟她做爱的想法 却发展成了疯狂的执念
but the idea of it became this wild obsession for me.
天啊
Oh God.
有人伤害了你 对吧?
Someone hurt you, didn't they?
在我设想过的 玛莎有可能干出的所有疯狂事里
Out of all the things I expected Martha to do next,
修复好我崩坏的性能力绝对不在其列
fixing my broken libido wasn't one of them.
我也讨厌它的回归令泰瑞如此开心
And I hated how happy it made Teri too.
我已经什么都不知道了
I didn't know anything anymore,
不知这一切将如何收场 所以在肆虐的惶惑中
so, in a tailspin as to where this all might end,
我仿佛感觉再次受到了凌虐
I felt abused again.
可以确定的是 如今有了警方的介入 她不会傻到再轻举妄动了
Surely with the police now involved, she'd be foolish to do anything else.
你列好时间线了吗?
Have you put together a timeline?
还没有 抱歉 我...
Uh, not yet. Sorry, I... I...
我还没想好该怎么写
I haven't found the words.
没关系 等你写好了再交给我们就行
Well, no problem. Just get it to us when you can.
我们跟史考特女士谈过了
So we spoke to Ms. Scott.
她怎么说?
What did she say?
结果发现她出奇地配合
well, she was surprisingly cooperative in the end.
真的吗?
Really?
她说她感到很羞愧 还表示愿意接受我们的帮助
She said she was embarrassed and went on to accept our offer of help.
事实上 自从那次谈话后 她已经去听了两节
In fact, she has attended two of our social-adjustment courses
我们提供的 社会适应课程?
since we last spoke to her. Social-adjustment courses?
通常是给长期服刑后 刑满释放的人员开设的
It's usually for ex-convicts who have done lengthy prison sentences,
但对惯犯也有帮助
but it helps with reoffenders as well.
她还说了别的什么吗?
So, did she say anything else?
没有会引人担忧的内容
Nothing that causes concern.
也没传递出任何信息吗?
She didn't, like, pass anything on?
我想不到有哪些不对劲
Nothing that comes to mind.
但她很生气 对吧? 我是说 她当时一定气炸了
But she was upset, right? I mean, she must have been upset.
没有 她其实接受得很好
No. No, she took it quite well, actually.
那这事就到此为止了?
So, that's it, then?
是的
That's it.
如果她再联系你 我们会把案件移交皇家检控署
If she contacts you again, we'll move the process on to the CPS,
他们会做出司法决策
who will decide the judicial outcome,
结果很可能是 法院会对她下达全面限制令
and likely result in you obtaining a full restraining order.
你可以喘口气了 唐尼
You can breathe out now, Donny.
什么? 她就坦然接受了?
So, what? She just accepted it?
是啊 很奇怪吧? 我以为她至少会嘴硬几句呢
Yeah. Strange, right? I at least thought she'd say something back.
再编造点东西什么的 但结果看来 她非常合作
You know, make shit up. But, apparently, she was very cooperative.
太诡异了
Weird.
还以为我们已经看透她了呢
You think you know someone.
是啊
Yeah.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
没有你期待的大决战 失望了?
Not the big showdown you were hoping for?
我不知道 只是感觉很奇怪 原来一直以来 她还是有自制力的
I don't know. It's just, like, odd that she had self-restraint all along.
让我不禁会想 也许她原本就没那么疯
Makes me think she wasn't all that mad to begin with.
现在你听起来才像个疯子
Now you're talking like the crazy one.
我才没疯 四万家律师事务所可不这么认为
I'm not crazy. 40,000 law firms say otherwise!
嘿 我们现在谈论的 好歹是个精神病人
Hey, this is still a mentally ill woman that we're talking about here.
好吧
Okay, okay.
我毕竟是一名治疗师
I'm still a therapist.
不能被人看见我放纵自己
I can't be seen indulging...
你的模仿太拙劣了 驯鹿宝贝
...rank impressions, baby reindeer,
而且还用毫无根据的谎言诋毁我
baseless lies and slander.
这是什么鬼?
What was that?
你这是在模仿玛莎吗? 天哪
Was that... Was that a Martha impression? Wow.
谁打来的?
Who's that?
我妈妈
It's my mum.
快接吧 我很好奇 要评判男人的人品 从他对待母亲的方式就可见一斑
Get it. I'm intrigued. You can always judge a man by how he treats his mother.
你他妈的到底想怎样?
What the fuck do you want?
开玩笑的 我还没接呢
I'm only joking. I haven't picked up.
我晚点再回拨给她 今晚是属于我们的二人世界
I'll get back to her later. This night is for us.
来
Here.
敬新的开始
To new beginnings.
- 你想好点什么了吗? - 还没 你呢 要点什么?
- Do you know what you're having? No idea. What are you getting?
我通常只会选 我知道名字该怎么念的菜品
I usually pick the only thing I can pronounce on the menu,
所以我就来份猪肘好了
so I think it's the ham hock for me.
第一条新语音信息 留言时间 28号 星期日 晚上8点28分
First new message, received Sunday 28th at 8:28 p.m.
你快接电话好吗? 我们到处给医院打电话
Will you pick up? We've been ringing every hospital
因为不知道你被送去了哪一家
to figure out which one you've been taken to.
问谁都说不知道 所以你能不能...
Nobody knows a thing, so if you would--
电话给我 我来说 儿子 快他妈的接电话
Give me that, will you? Son, pick up your bastard phone.
我们坐在这干着急 不知道该往哪走
We're sitting here wondering where the fuck to go.
听说你出车祸了 但我们问了半天
Nobody has any records of you anywhere,
没有人知道你在哪 也没有任何记录
or a car crash or anything we've been told.
告诉我们究竟发生了什么事
So tell us what's going on.
我们回拨给之前打电话来的那个人 也打不通
We can't get back through to the person who called either.
她叫什么名字来着?
What's her fucking name?
玛莎
Martha.
根据理查德·加德的话剧 《驯鹿宝贝》改编